Now one of the concepts that we haven't gone over yet is actually going to be events.
现在还有一个概念我们没有介绍，那就是“事件”("Events")
And events are really important to our smart contracts.
对于智能合约来说 "Events" 是非常重要的
Whenever we update a dynamic object, like an array or a mapping,
当我们更新动态对象，比如说数组或映射时
we always want to omit an event
我们总是希望能触发 Event
when we get to less than 10.
当我们前进到 "Lesson 10"
And then especially less than 15 with the next Jas and if T marketplace,
尤其是 "Lesson 15: NextJS NFT Marketplace" 的时候
these events will make a ton of sense, especially for front end developers.
这些 Events 就会变得更有意义，尤其是对前端开发者来说
So right now events might be a little bit of a weird thing for you as we explain it.
现在，我们对 Event 的解释可能会让你感觉有些奇怪
But as we continue on, they'll start to make more and more sense.
但让我们保持前进，它们会开始变得越来越有意义的
So we're going to start adding events to our smart contracts.
因此，我们要为我们的智能合约添加 Event
Whenever we update one of these dynamically sized data structures.
每当我们更新动态大小的数据结构时
And to learn more about events and how to use them.
要想了解更多有关 Events 的信息以及如何使用它们
We're gonna watch another video that explains all about events.
我们可以观看另一个视频，它解释了有关 Events 的所有内容
You can actually follow along with this video as a side project.
你可以把这个视频当做一个并行项目
But let's learn all about events.
让我们来全面了解一下 Events
Now, if you've worked with solidity,
如果你正在使用 Solidity 工作
you've probably seen these things called events before
那么你可能之前见到过这些被称为 Events 的东西
or maybe you haven't seen something like events.
或者也可能并没有见过
But you've always wondered how chain link or the graph or some of these other off chain protocols work under the hood.
但你或许会经常好奇 Chainlink、The Graph 或是其它离链协议的底层工作原理
And in this video, we're gonna learn about logging and events in solidity,
在这个视频中，我们会了解 Solidity 中的 "Logging" 以及 "Events"
viewing those events on ether scan,
在 etherscan 上查看 Events
and then working with them in hard hat.
以及在 Hardhat 中使用它们
Now it's the Ethereum virtual machine, or EVM.
"Ethereum Virtual Machine" 或者说 "EVM"
That makes a lot of these block chains tick, like Aetherium.
是驱动许多区块链平台的核心，比如以太坊
And the EVM has this functionality called a logging functionality.
EVM 有一种名为 "Logging" 的功能
When things happen on a blockchain,
当区块链上发生某些事情的时候
the EVM writes these things to a specific data structure called its log,
EVM 会把这些事情写入到一种名为 "Logs" 的特殊数据结构中
we can actually read these logs from our blockchain nodes that we run.
我们可以从我们运行的区块链节点中阅读这些 "Logs"
In fact, if you run a node or you connect to a node,
事实上，如果你运行一个节点或连接到一个节点
you can make a F get logs call to get the logs.
你就可以通过调用 "eth_getLogs" 来获取 "Logs"
Now inside these logs is an important piece of logging called events.
在 Logging 中有一个很重要的部分，名为 "Events"
And this is the main piece that we're gonna be talking about today.
这就是我们今天要主要谈论的部分
events allow you to print information to this logging structure
Events 可以让你将信息打印到 Logging 结构中
in a way that's more gas efficient than actually saving it to something like a storage variable.
这种方式要比实际保存到诸如 storage 变量的方式更节省 gas
These events and logs live in this special data structure that isn't accessible to smart contracts.
Events 和 Logs 存在于一种智能合约无法访问的特殊数据结构中
That's why it's cheaper because smart contracts can access them
这就是为什么它更加便宜，因为智能合约无法访问它们
so that If the trade off here, we can still print some information that's important to us
在这种权衡下，我们仍然可以给自己打印一些关键的信息
without having to save it in a storage variable, which is going to take up much more gas.
但无需再保存到 storage 变量中了，因为这样做会消耗我们更多的 gas
Each one of these events is tied to the smart contract or account address that emitted this event in these transactions.
每一个 Event 都与在交易中发出该 Event 的智能合约或账户地址相关联
listening for these events is incredibly helpful.
监听这些 Events 是非常有帮助的
Let's say for example, you want to do something every time somebody calls a transfer function.
让我们来举个例子，假设你想要在每次有人调用转账函数时执行某个操作
Instead of always reading all the variables and looking for something to flip and switch,
与其总是读取所有变量然后寻找需要转换的内容
all you have to do is say, listen for event.
你倒不如直接监听 Event
So a transaction happened, an event is emitted. And we can listen for these events.
也就是说，某个交易发生，接着 Event 触发，然后我们就可以监听这些 Event
This is how a lot of off chain infrastructure works.
这就是许多离链基础设施的工作方式
When you're on a website, and that website reloads when a transaction completes,
当你使用网页时，它会在交易完成的时候自动刷新
it actually was listening for that transaction to finish listening for that event to be emitted,
实际上它做的就是监听这个交易完成时触发的 Event
so that it could reload or it could do something else.
这样它就可以进而刷新，或者做一些别的什么事了
It's incredibly important for front ends.
对于前端来说这尤为重要
It's also incredibly important for things like chain link, and the graph
对于 Chainlink 和 "The Graph" 来说，这同样非常重要
in the chain link network. A chain link node is actually listening for request data events
在 Chainlink 网络中，一个 Chainlink 节点所做的事，实际上就是监听请求数据的 Event
for to get a random number, make an API call, or etc.
以执行获取随机数，调用 API 等操作
Sometimes there are way too many events. And you need to index them in a way that makes sense
有的时候 Event 太多了，你就需要以某种有意义的方式来进行索引
that you can query all these events that happen at a later date.
以便在未来的某个日子里查询所有这些已发生的 Event
The graph listens for these events and stores them in the graph so that they're easy to query later on.
"The Graph" 会监听并存储这些 Event，以便以后可以轻松地进行查询
So events are incredibly powerful. And they have a wide range of uses.
Event 十分强大，并且受到了广泛地应用
They're also good for testing and some other stuff, but you get the picture. They're really sick.
它们对于测试和其它一些事情同样非常有用，懂了吧，它们真的很牛
Now that we know what events are, let's look at what they look like
现在我们已经知道 Event 是什么了，让我们来看一下它们到底是什么样的
how we can use them and how we might use them in our smart contract development suite.
以及我们该如何使用它们，尤其是在智能合约开发包中如何使用它们
Now here's what an event is going to look like. We have an event here called stored number.
那么，一个 Event 就是长这样的，这是一个名为 "storedNumber" 的 Event
So we have basically a new type of event called stored number.
基本上意思就是，我们有了一种新的 Event 数据类型名为 "storedNumber"
We're saying, hey, solidity, hey, smart contract, we have this new event thing,
相当于再说，嘿，Solidity，嘿，智能合约，我们有一个新的 Event
we're going to be omitting things of typed stored number in the future.
未来我们会触发这种 "storedNumber" 类型的 Event
When we emit this event, it's going to have these four parameters,
我们要触发的这个 Event 有四个参数
it's going to have a unique 256. For called old number. Are you interested? Is it called new number are you intimidated six called add a number and an address called center.
分别是 "uint256 oldNumber", "uint256 newNumber", "uint256 addedNumber" 以及 "address sender"
Now for the astute people here, you might have noticed that there was another keyword in here,
有些机智的人可能已经注意到了，这里还有另外一个关键字
the index to keyword and this is a really important keyword.
就是 "indexed" 关键字，这是一个非常重要的关键字
When we omit one of these events, there are two kinds of parameters,
当我们触发某个 Event 的时候，它会有两种参数
there are the index parameters and the non indexed parameters,
分别是 "indexed" 参数以及非 "indexed" 参数
you can have up to three index parameters. And they're also known as topics.
你最多可以有三个 "indexed" 参数，它们也被称为 "Topics"
So if you see a topic, you know that that's going to be an indexed parameter.
所以如果你看到了 "Topic" 就会知道，这是一个 "indexed" 参数
Index parameters are parameters that are much easier to search for, and much easier to query than the non index parameters.
"indexed" 参数是一种更容易搜索的参数，相比于非 "indexed" 参数而言
In fact, we recommend F get logs function, it even has a parameter allows us to search for specific topics.
事实上，我们推荐使用 "eth_getLogs" 函数，它甚至有一个参数可以让我们直接搜索特定的 "Topic"
So it's much more searchable than the non indexed ones.
所以相对于非 "indexed" 参数而言，它的可搜索性要更强
The non indexed ones are harder to search because they get ABI encoded, and you have to know the API in order to decode them.
非 "indexed" 参数由于被 ABI 编码过，因此搜索起来更加困难，你必须要知道相应的 ABI 才能对它们进行解码
Now, this is told our smart contract that there is a new type of stored number, a new kind of event here,
现在，我们已经告诉智能合约，这里有一种新的 "storedNumber" 类型，一个新的 Event
we need to actually emit that event in order to store that data into the logging data structure of the EVM.
我们需要实际触发这个 Event，才能将数据存储到 Logging 数据结构中
To do that, we need to do something that looks like this.
为了做到这一点，我们需要像这样做
This is what it looks like when we emit an event, it looks very similar to calling a function.
当我们触发("emit") Event 时就会呈现这样的效果，看起来和调用函数非常类似
So you call a mitt and then the name of the event.
也就是，调用 "emit" 后面跟着的是这个 Event 的名字
And then you add all the parameters in there that you like.
然后你可以添加你想要的所有参数
Here's the full example of a smart contract that has an event and is going to be the example that we walked through in hard hat.
这是一个完整的包含 Event 的智能合约示例，并且我们也会在 Hardhat 中使用这个例子
Now in this smart contract, whenever anybody calls the store function, we're going to omit this event.
现在在这个智能合约里，每当有人调用 "store" 函数，我们就会触发这个 Event
Here's an example of a transaction where we call the store function with a value of one,
这里有一个交易的例子，其中我们使用数字 1 调用了 "store" 函数
（译者注：屏幕上实际显示的数字是 0 和 77）
let's look into the logs to see what this event actually is going to look like
让我们来查看一下 Logs 看看这个 Event 实际上是什么样子的
an event is going to be broken down like so
一个 Event 会被解析为以下这样
the address of the contract or account, the event is emitted from
这是是合约或账户的地址("Address")，也是 Event 被触发的来源
the topics or the index parameters of the event
这里是 Event 的 "Topics" 或者说 "indexed" 参数
data. This is the ABI encoded non index parameters of the event.
"Data"，这是 Event 中经过 ABI 解码后的非 "indexed" 参数
What does this mean? This means that we took those parameters that were non indexed,
这意味着什么呢？这意味着我们获取了这些非 "indexed" 参数
we match them together with their API or application binary interface,
并将它们与 ABI 或者说 "Application Binary Interface" 进行了匹配
pumped them through an encoding algorithm, and boom, this is what we got.
我们将它们扔进了编码算法中，然后嘭，这就是我们得到的结果
If you have the API, they're very easy to decode.
如果你拥有 ABI，它们就非常容易解码
If you don't have the ABI they are very hard to decode
如果你没有 ABI ，它们就非常不容易解码
these non indexed parameters cost less gas to pump into the logs.
这些非 "indexed" 参数放入 Logs 的时候会消耗更少的 gas
Now in this particular contract, since we have verified the code, we verified the contract
现在，在这个合约中，由于我们已经验证过了代码，验证过了合约
ether scan knows what the ABI is, and we can view this in Deke or decoded mode.
所以 etherscan 知道它的 ABI 是什么，因此我们可以使用 "Dec" 或者说解码模式("Decoded Mode")来进行查看
Hex mode is obviously the non decoded mode, or in its raw, hex or hexadecimal or encoded mode.
"Hex" 模式显然就是非解码模式，或者说它是原始的，十六进制的，编码模式的
You can read more about the layout of these events in the solidity docs.
你可以在 Solidity 文档中阅读到更多这些有关 Event 布局的内容
Now, so that's the basic introduction of events.
这就是 Event 的一个基础的介绍
And for those of you who want to watch the rest of that video, and who wants to actually practice using events yourself,
对于那些想要观看该视频剩余部分，以及想亲自练习使用 Event 的人来说
there's a link to these videos and the code repository associated with that video,
这里有这个视频以及这个视频相关的代码库的链接
if you want to play with it, and if you want to learn more,
如果你要亲自试一试或者学习更多内容的话
so feel free Ready to refer back to the full blockchain solidity course, Jas, if you want to go deeper into events
如果你要更深入地了解 Event 的话，可以自由选择何时回到 "full-blockchain-solidity-course-js" 这里来
now that we're back, and we've learned a little bit more about events, let's add some events to this contract.
现在我们回来了，并且已经学习了一些关于 Event 的知识，让我们来给这个合约添加一些 Event 吧
Remember, these events get emitted to a data storage outside of this smart contract.
请记住，这些被触发的 Event 会被送到智能合约之外的数据存储中
Let's create an event called raffle enter a good syntax for naming events,
让我们来创建一个名为 "RaffleEnter" 的 Event，这是一个很好的 Event 命名法
name events, with the function name reversed.
`// Named events with the function name reversed`
（“把函数名反过来以命名 Event”）
So for enter raffle, we're gonna say raffle entered.
所以对于 "enterRaffle" 来说我们要命名成 "RaffleEnter"
So up at the top below our state variables, but above our constructor,
所以来到顶部，在我们的 "State Variables" 的下面，"constructor" 的上面
we'll create a new section called events.
我们要创建一个新的部分，名为 `/* Events */`
And we'll create our first event.
接着我们来创建一下我们的第一个 Event
So we'll do event, raffle, Enter.
`event RaffleEnter()`
And we'll just have this raffle enter take one index parameter, it'll be an address indexed player.
我们在 "RaffleEnter" 中只输入一个 "indexed" 参数，也就是 `address indexed player`
So in our Inter raffle, we're going to say omit raffle enter. And we're just going to pass it message dot sender.
在我们的 "enterRaffle" 里，我们要写 `emit RaffleEnter()` 传入 `msg.sender` 作为参数
I'm going to remove these comments for now. But feel free to leave them in as you code along.
我现在要把这些注释都删掉，你自己写代码的时候可以选择保留下来
Now in this part of my raffle coding or my lottery coding process,
在我们的抽奖或者说彩票的代码编写过程中
I probably would start already writing some tests and already writing some deploy scripts.
我可能会提前开始编写测试还有部署脚本
The reason that we do this is it's good to test our functionality as we progress.
之所以要这样做是为了在编程的过程中测试我们的功能是否完善良好
And oftentimes, when I'm writing smart contracts, I'm constantly flipping back and forth between my deploy scripts, my contracts and my tests
通常，在我编写智能合约时，我会不断地在部署脚本，合约以及测试之间来回切换
to make sure everything is doing exactly what I want it to do
以确保所有的事情都能完全按照我的期望进行
for the purpose of this course. And just to make it easy for you to learn and follow along, we're not going to do that.
为了达到这门课的目的，也为了能让你们的学习和跟进能够更加轻松，我们就不这么做了
And we're just going to keep writing our smart contract
我们会持续编写我们的智能合约
almost to complete and then move to our deploy scripts and tests.
直到几乎完成之后才会转向部署脚本和测试上